Guide to the Glenn H. Beyer papers,1934-1969.
Beyer, Glenn H. papers,1934-1969.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Glenn H. Beyer papers, 1934-1969.
53-4-1548
Glenn H. Beyer, 1913-1969.
10.3 cubic ft.
Manuscripts, gallery proofs, correspondence, questionnaires, photographs, research material, notes, printed materials, film strips, monographs, and articles.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Manuscripts and galley proofs; correspondence; questionnaires; photographs, negatives, and slides; research material, notes, and rough drafts pertaining to rural housing; printed materials; and 2 victrola records and 3 film strips relating to the 1950 census.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Glenn Beyer was born in Chester, South Dakota in 1913. He earned degrees from Augustana (South Dakota) College in 1935 and George Washington University in 1939. He held positions in several federal housing agencies until he became Professor of Housing and Design at Cornell University in 1947. He became Director of the Cornell Center for Housing and Environmental Studies (formerly the Housing Research Center) upon its establishment in 1950. Beyer wrote several books, monographs, and articles on rural and farm housing and housing for the elderly. Many works were concerned with Upstate New York housing practices.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Manuscripts and galley proofs; correspondence; questionnaires; photographs, negatives, and slides; research material, notes, and rough drafts pertaining to rural housing; printed materials; and 2 victrola records and 3 film strips relating to the 1950 census.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Beyer, Glenn H., 1913-1969.; Beyer, Glenn H.; Cornell University--Faculty.
Subjects:
Housing--New York (State); Housing, Rural.; Aged--Dwellings.; College teachers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Galley proofs.; Motion pictures.; Negatives.; Photographs.; Questionnaires.; Color slides.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Chronological Correspondence Files, 1955-1969
Series II. Subject Files
Series III. Photographs
Series IV. Printed Material
Series V. Miscellany
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Chronological Correspondence Files, 1955-1969
  - July-August, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - September, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - October, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - November, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - December, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - January, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - February-March, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - April-May, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - June, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - July-August, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - September-October, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - November, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - December, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - January-February, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - March, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - April-May, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - June, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - July-August, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - September-October, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - November-December, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - January-February, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - March-April, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - May-June, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - July-August, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - September-October, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - November-December, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - January-February, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - March-April, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - May-June, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - July-August, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - September-October, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - November-December, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - January, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - February-March, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - April-June, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - July-September, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - October-December, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - January-February, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - March-May, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - June-July, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - August-December, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - January-May, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - June-July, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - September, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - October, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - November-December, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - January-March, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - April-May, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - June-July, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - August-October, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - November-December, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - January-February, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - March-April, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - May-July, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - August-September, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - October-December, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - January-February, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - March-April, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - May, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - June-July, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - August, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - September, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - October, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - November-December, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - January, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - February-April, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - May-July, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - August-September, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - October-December, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - January-March, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - April-August, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - September-December, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - January-May, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - June-August, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - September-December, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - January-May, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - June-December, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Series II. Subject Files
  - Biographical files related to work, 1939-1963 (Box 23, Folder 12-14)
  - Agency for International Development (AID), 1964-1968 (Box 3, Folder 25-27)
  - Agency for International Development (AID) - official papers and authorizations (including WCI), 1964-1968 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Agency for International Development (AID) - 7539 contract and amendments; detailed work plan; standardized regulations, 1963-1969 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - American University Course, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - "Analysis of Housing Need in Oak Ridge" (see also box 14), 1950 (Box 3, Folder 31-32)
  - "An Economic Appraisal of the Miami Metropolitan Area with Emphasis on Miami Beach", 1954 (Box 4, Folder 1-6)
  - Application for research grant - architecture, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Articles - published and unpublished, 1962-1968 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Article: Neighborhoods - personal, not published, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bathroom, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Beyer - articles, talks, comments, papers, 1948-1966 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Carreiro, Joseph - Search Committee for Chairmanship, Department of Housing and Design, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Carter, Lisle C. - Center for Housing and Environmental Studies, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Climate Study, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - College of Architecture, 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
  - College of Architecture - faculty meetings, 1960-1966 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Columbia University demonstration, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - "The Community Land Use Game", 1966 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Conference on Building Documentation, 1953-1958 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Conference on Methodology in Housing Research North-East Regional Housing Research Project NE-7, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Contracts, agreements, 1948-1951 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Department of Housing and Urban Development, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Documentation, 1954-1958 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Documentation, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 26-27)
  - Documentation Study - Ford Proposal, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Extended Monroe County survey, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - FHA - Industrialized Housing Branch, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Federal-State aging, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Ford Foundation - India trip, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Galley (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Hotel Project no. 453, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Houses are for People, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 35-37)
  - Houses are for People, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 38-39)
  - Housing: A Factual Analysis - Reader's Reports, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Housing Center Report, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Housing for Aged - Ford Foundation (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Housing Materials Study (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Concerning housing research, 1959-1967 (Box 5, Folder 3-5)
  - Housing Research Center brochure, Cornell University, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Housing Research Center Values Study -draft of report, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Housing Value Studies, 1950-1952 (Box 5, Folder 8-10)
  - "Important Documents", 1950-1967 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - India (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - India - Housing Mission (Ford Foundation), 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
  - "India's Urban Housing - a Report to the Ford Foundation", 1965 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Low Income Housing Area Survey - WPA, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 17-20)
  - Lustron House - Excerpts from Final Report, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Lutheran Association of Ithaca, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - McGraw Housing, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Mailing lists, miscellaneous, etc. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Market study on residential air conditioning, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Material on Hired Man, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Memos to Long from Glen and Barclay, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Middle-income housing and rehabilitation, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Minutes - code (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Newsclippings, pamphlets, articles, etc. from scrapbook (Box 5, Folder 30-34)
  - Newsclippings, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - New York State Commerce Review, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - The Next Fifty Years - 1967-2017, includes C. Abrams Paper "Housing in the Year 2000" with Remarks by G.H. Beyer (to Ewald), 1967 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - North Eastern Commuting Study, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Outline for research proposals (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Papers, testimonies, 1959-1964 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Permissions, 1956-1958 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Permission file, 1956-1959 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Personal - Beyer sabbatic, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 43-44)
  - Personal, 1962-1968 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - "Plastics in Building Trade" (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Publications from the Cornell Studies in Intergroup Relations, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Public Housing, miscellany, 1951-1969 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Public Housing Research Proposal (Social Effects of Public Housing), 1953-1955 (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
  - Puerto Rico, 1967-1969 (Box 6, Folder 4-7)
  - Prefab Study, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 8-10)
  - President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - President's Committee to Study Low-Cost Ithaca Housing (Mackesey - chairman; O. Winston - vice-chairman), 1969 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "Proposal to the Agency for International Development from Cornell University ... Urban Housing Policy in Latin America...", 1965 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Proposal to Study the Housing Needs of the Elderly, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Reading file, September-December, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 15-17)
  - Reading file, January-March, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 18-20)
  - Reading file, April-June, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 21-23)
  - Reading file, July-December, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 24-26)
  - Reading file, October, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Reconstruction Finance Corporation (RFC) - Greenport Basin Case, 1947-1958 (Box 6, Folder 28-29)
  - "Report on Housing in the Bahama Islands" (see also box 14), 1968 (Box 6, Folder 30-31)
  - Regional Housing Survey Laboratory, 1949-1955 (Box 6, Folder 32-33)
  - "Research Methods for Housing and Urbanization Studies in Developing Countries" by Margaret E. Woods and Earl W. Morris, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 34-39)
  - Research Needed in Urban Land Use and Housing, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - No. 8 Reynolds Metal Company, 1945-1955 (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
  - Rural Housing Study, Cortland County, NY, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 1-7)
  - Sabbatic correspondence, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
  - Search Committee - Deanship of Home Economics, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
  - Secondary Farm Housing (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "Shelter and Care for the Aging in Western Countries" (tentative book title), Austria, Denmark, England (see also 8-6), 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "Shelter and Care for the Aging in Western Countries" (tentative book title), Finland, France, Germany, Italy, Netherlands, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "Shelter and Care for the Aging in Western Countries" (tentative book title), Norway, Scotland, Sweden, Switzerland (see also 8-7), 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "Shelter and Care for the Aging in Western Countries" (tentative book title), United States, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
  - Stockholm trip - UN conference (correspondence) (pd. from CHES), 1968 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Study of Bathroom Equipment and Planning Requirements, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Sweden, 1962-1968 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Sympathy notes, greeting cards, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 17-19)
  - Tape recordings while abroad, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - U.S.-Mexican seminar, Mexico City, sponsored by HEW, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - USDA - Marketing and Research Study schedules, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - University faculty minutes and notices, 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 22-25)
  - University Long Range Planning Committee, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - The Urban Explosion in Latin America galley proof (partial) and index (?), 1967 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Urbanization book permissions, 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Values proposal #3, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Woodshole - conference (with Department of Housing and Urban Development), 1966 (Box 7, Folder 30-31)
  - Youngstown Kitchens, 1954-1960 (Box 7, Folder 32-35)
  - Bahamas (see also box 6) (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
  - Oak Ridge, Tenn. housing (see also box 3), 1948 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Venezuela, H.P. Greep Memorandum on Housing Finance in, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "Shelter and Care for the Aging in Western Countries" (see also 8-6) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Shelter and Care for the Aging in Western Countries" (see also 8-7) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Miscellany (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Series III. Photographs
  - Broome County #1-#304 (Box 9)
  - Broome County #305-#441 (Box 10)
  - Chemung County #1-105 (Box 10)
  - Chemung County #106-#189 (Box 11)
  - Clinton County #1-#155 (Box 11)
  - Clinton County #156-#410 (Box 12)
  - Dutchess County #6-#19 (Box 12)
  - Dutchess County #20-#311 (Box 13)
  - Dutchess County #312-#648 (Box 14)
  - Dutchess County #649-#741 (Box 15)
  - Monroe County #1-#127 (Box 15)
  - Monroe County #128-#327 (Box 16)
  - Monroe County #328-#564 (Box 17)
  - "Pictures of houses pulled as possible cover for NE 20 Publication" (Box 18)
  - Slides and photos (and negatives) re housing, include European housing for elderly (Box 8)
  - Kitchens and pre-fabricated houses - photographs and glass slides (also index cards of kitchen supplies) (Box 19)
- Series IV. Printed Material
  - Publications (Box 21)
  - Papers written by Beyer as a graduate student, 1935-1938 (Box 23, Folder 1-10)
  - Paper written by Beyer as a professor, 1966-1969 (Box 23, Folder 11)
- Series V. Miscellany
  - Day books, notebooks (Box 20)
  - Photograph album: "Lustron" (Box 22)
  - Scrapbook on housing, kitchens, etc. (Box 22)
  - Photostat copy of large greeting card: "Season's Greetings, 1966-1967", 1966-1967 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Diploma froom Mexico, 1966-11-12 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Yearbook from Augustana College in Sioux Falls, South Dakota, 1934 (Box 23)
  - Diploma from Augustana College in Sioux Fall, South Dakota, 1935 (Box 23)
  - Medal and Citation from Augustana College in Sioux Falls, South Dakota, 1960 (Box 23)
  - Address book (Box 23)